

## **SERGE ILYASHENKO**

**Front-end Developer** 

linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com">https://www.linkedin.com</a>...
github: <a href="https://github.com/serjily...">https://github.com/serjily...</a>
twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/SkySerj">https://twitter.com/SkySerj</a>

Download a PDF version

# **SUMMARY**

Passionate Front-End Developer with large experience of creating enterprise SPA applications. Skills include analytical thinking and focusing on problem solving. Able to find and apply solution project needs taking care about company goals. Taking care about project code-style. Well interact with team and with external departments.

### **KEY SKILLS**

CSS GraphQL JavaScript HTML React Redux MobX **Hard Skills** Data-Driven Documents (D3) **TypeScript** Webpack **Ember** WebSockets KnockoutJs **Soft Skills** Communication Curiosity Adaptability Mentoring

# PRIOR WORK EXPERIENCE

### **dMetrics**

Front-end Developer May 2019 - Present.

### Al platform

The tool allows to use AI with no data science experience.

Tech stack:

React, Redux, Webpack, GraphQL.

### ZenSoft

Front-end Developer Sep. 2016 - May 2019

### **Tracking platform**

The system allowed to track project's budget, progress and timelines during every sprint. This helped to improve and optimize process of developing.

#### Personal achievements:

Proposition and integration of TypeScript technology to the project. This
well decreased bug amount on coding stage.

Tech stack:

TypeScript, React, MobX, Webpack.

### Web Platform form managing media ads

Personal achievements:

Completed the project in 3 months in terms of a hard deadline.

Tech stack.

TypeScript, React, Redux, Webpack.

### **Blockchain platform**

Makes it easy for developers to connect their applications to multiple blockchain networks with no blockchain experience

Personal achievements:

- The development of the module for smart contact versioning. This allowed to change smart contracts during working process
- Proposition and implementation of the personal credential encoding for the additional security. The credentials are safe even if access file fall into the hands of intruders.

Tech stack:

TypeScript, React, Redux, Webpack, web3 + MetaMask.

### Reference Data Management enterprise system

It allowed the customer to avoid overtimes during reporting period.

Personal achievements:

- · Created a front-end team of 5 people for working on the project
- · Raised 2 junior devs into middle devs
- Proposition and implementation of the real-time update solution using WebSocket technology. This raised user experience to a new level and allowed to decrease server load.

Tech stack:

EmberJS, WebSockets, Stomp - PubSub protocol.

### **Landing Page optimization**

Personal achievements:

- Halved the number of server requests from 114 to 70
- Eliminated droppings to 30FPS while scrolling
- Loading time reduced by 30sec

Tech stack:

JS, jQuery.

# AllVision / Minsk, Belarus

Front-end Developer Mar. 2012 — Sep. 2016

### Monitoring and control systems

Allows to configure IoT-like systems using smartphone or tablet.

### Personal achievements:

• Provided support for TCP, http and RS based protocols.

### Tech stack:

JS, jQuery, C, NodeJs.

# ATOMTEX / Minsk, Belarus

Software Tester Aug. 2011 — Mar. 2012

### Monitoring software for radio emission spectrometers

Personal achievements:

• On this position like QA tester I really understood how important testing. And now I always spend time for looking for critical bugs in my code.

### Tech stack:

JS, jQuery, C, NodeJs.

### **EDUCATION**

# Belorusian State University

Nuclear Physics and Electronics Sep. 2007 — Jul. 2012

### **Personal achievements:**

Developed the boot loader for Microchip micro-controllers throw usb interface.

### Tech stack:

HTML/CSS/JS, C++.

# ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- · Publications on the medium.com resource
- Open Source contribution
- Taking part in JS conferences and workshops